Steven Basart Computer Science PhD student

xksteven.com xksteven at uchicago.edu (954) 805-3651

Research Interests

My current research in computer science is in the field of computer vision. For the years of 2016-2017 I have worked on generative models, specifically GANs. I have begun investigation into reinforcement learning techniques and their applications into computer vision. My research focuses on the uses of machine learning.

Education

Doctor of Philosophy (Computer Science) 2014 to ongoing

University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois

Bachelor of Science (Biochemistry and Computer Science) 2010 to 2014

University of Miami, Miami, Florida

Courses

Machine Learning Robot Planning/AI Computer Vision

Algorithms Databases

Teaching

TA for Machine Learning (Autumn 2017)

TA for Intro. to Computer Science (Autumn 2016)

TA for Intro. to Computer Science (Winter 2016) TA for Machine
Learning(Spring 2016)

TA for Computational Biology (Autumn 2015)

Research Experience

Computer Science 2014 to current

I am working with Dr. Greg Shakhnarovich at TTIC in the areas of machine learning and computer vision on the problem of visual question answering. I have worked with Torch to create various neural network models.

Biochemistry 2011 to 2014

I worked with Dr. Richard Myers at the University of Miami trying to create a generic genetic therapy via transducible gene editing proteins. I ran western blots, gel electrophoresis, transductions, PCR, and electroporation

Technical

Python Javascript / NodeJS

Git / SVN MySQL OpenGL

Experience

Google Brain Research Intern Summer 2018

I worked in NLP and collaborated with several teams. I worked in the area of Fact Checking related to this paper to deal with the problem of content abuse and also worked with the news team. **python**, **pytorch**, **tensorflow**, **apache-beam**, **flume**

Here Maps Research Intern Summer 2017

I worked on models to better predict arrival times (ETA estimates) and lane level navigation prediction which can be used for autonomous vehicles. **python**, **pytorch**

Here Maps Research Intern Summer 2016

I developed a model that creates road probability maps that can be used to detect differences between artificial maps and the real roads. **python, tensorflow**

Projects

OpenGL Renderer

myRenderer

I created a simple OpenGL renderer to render some height maps and draw some objects. Applies simple lighting and texturing.

BattleShip game over internet

BattleShip

I created a simple Battleship game in C that has a client, server interface.